# HANIYEH FATHOLAHI

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Email: haniyeh.fath@gmail.com

Address: Dortmund, North Rhine-Westphalia, Germany

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/h-fatholahi



## **SUMMARY**

I am a software engineer with more than 5 years of work experience in medium-sized and large companies providing software solutions in the fields of intelligent transportation, fleet tracking, payment and insurance systems. Also, I am skilled in system analysis, design and backend development.

my expertise is developing applications and APIs using Java and NodeJS including their related frameworks, technologies and tools like different databases - SQL and NoSQL databases. In addition, experienced in developing services for IoT devices such as management and communication services.

#### **EXPERIENCES**

MAY 2021 - MAR 2022

# JAVA DEVELOPER IN INSURANCE CORE INSURANCE, DOTIN, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Designing and developing new functionalities for life insurance system
- Developing life insurance rest APIs
- Developing and support financial features
- Working on system optimization for high performances
- Cooperating with customers in order to achieve all SRS requirements and features

#### OCT 2016 - FEB 2021

## **R&D DEPARTMENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, MAGFA, TEHRAN**

My roles in the company:

- Designing and developing fleet tracking services for GPS tracking systems
- Designing and developing APIs for fleet tracking applications and services
- Collaborating with Frontend team
- Cooperating with hardware development team in order to design a new tracking protocol on top of TCP
- Designing and developing a USSD Wrapper service for USSD based mobile payments

#### SEP 2016 - MAR 2020

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TOOBATECH**, TEHRAN

My roles in the company:

- Technical lead of Toobatel Instant messaging system project for Alzahra university
- Designing and developing Toobatel app services such as gif and sticker services
- Integrating university services with Toobatel app
- Backend development for customized web applications such as polling and survey systems
- Developing services for other teams such as BI and AI teams

# **SKILLS**

	Solid Understanding	Worked With	Familiar with Or Intrigued by
Programming .	- Java	- JavaScript	- Typescript
languages	- NodeJS	- Python	0 "
Development tools/frameworks	<ul><li>Spring</li><li>Spring Boot</li><li>Hibernate</li><li>Express JS</li><li>JSF</li><li>Maven</li></ul>	- JPA - Swagger	- Gradle
Software engineering & methodologies	<ul><li>OOP</li><li>Agile</li><li>Scrum</li><li>System design</li><li>Debug and Tshoot</li></ul>	<ul><li>Design Patterns</li><li>GIT</li><li>CI/CD</li><li>Unit Testing</li><li>DDD</li></ul>	
Architecture	<ul><li>Microservice</li><li>MVC</li></ul>	- SOA	
Web technologies	<ul> <li>RESTful APIs</li> <li>SOAP Webservices</li> <li>JSON</li> <li>HTTP</li> <li>JSP/Servlet</li> <li>Socket programming</li> </ul>	- JWT - jUnit	
IDEs and tools	<ul> <li>IntelliJ idea</li> <li>Netbeans</li> <li>Eclipse</li> <li>Webstorm</li> <li>Postman</li> <li>iReport</li> <li>SQL developer</li> <li>argoUML</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Docker</li> <li>Apache tomcat</li> <li>verneMQ</li> <li>RabbitMQ</li> <li>Apache webserver</li> <li>Nginx</li> <li>jConsole</li> <li>jMeter</li> </ul>	<ul><li> Kubernetes</li><li> Jenkins</li><li> Kafka</li><li> Ansible</li></ul>
Databases	<ul><li>Oracle</li><li>MySQL</li><li>MongoDB</li><li>Redis</li></ul>	<ul><li>Neo4j</li><li>PostgreSQL</li><li>Cassandra</li></ul>	
OS	- Windows - CentOS	- Ubuntu	
Project/Source control tools	<ul><li>GitLab</li><li>BitBucket</li><li>Redmine</li><li>Jira</li></ul>	- Trello	

# **EDUCATION**

2012 - 2016

# BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SOFTWARE ENGINEERING, ALZAHRA UNIVERSITY,

**TEHRAN** 

Dissertation Title: "implementing IoT platform by customizing Openstack cloud computing Infrastructure APIs for collecting metrics from IoT nodes. "

# **CERTIFICATES**

- Oracle Database 12c administration, LAITEC institute of Sharif University of Technology, Tehran
- Java 8 Standard Edition, LAITEC institute of Sharif University of Technology, Tehran

# **LANGUAGES**

• **Persian:** Native

English: Fluent (TOEFL iBT certificate – C2)
 German: Basic (taking in A2 level classes)